Finding aid for George William Cushing Papers and sound recordings, 1942-1955
Bentley Historical Library
- In Our Opinion: recordings of programs, 7 in. reel-to-reel tapes; 7 1/2 ips
  - 1954
    - American Architecture, 1954 January 17; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 9)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-236-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Mr. Willem M. Dudok (Dutch Architect), Mr. Willard C. Wichers (Holland, Michigan), Mr. Willem Von Weiler (Netherlands Consul, Detroit).)
    - Crime Solving, 1954 January 24; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 9)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-237-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Mr. Raymond C. Schindler (Private Detective, NY).)
    - Japan, 1954 January 31; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 9)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-238-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Honorable Ronzo Sawada (Ambassador to the United Nations for Japan), Rt. Rev. Richard S. Emrich (Bishop of the Diocese of Michigan), Dr. Paul Rusch (Tokyo, Japan), Lt. Gen. C.H. Lee (Retired, York, Pa.).)
    - United Nations, 1954 February 07; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 9)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-239-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Dr. Archibald J. Carey, Jr. (United States Delegate to the United Nations).)
    - Mental Health, 1954 February 14; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 9)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-240-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Dr. Winfred Overholser (Superintendent of St. Elizabeth's Hospital), Dr. Jack R. Ewalt (Commissioner of Mental Health for State of Massachusetts).)
    - George Washington, 1954 February 21; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 9)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-241-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Mr. Kenneth Metcalf (Detroit Public Library).)
    - Rheumatic Fever, 1954 February 28; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 9)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-242-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Dr. Leon DeVel (Grand Rapids, Medical Coordinator of Rheumatic Fever Control, Michigan State Medical Society), Dr. John Bielawski (Detroit, Director of Michigan Heart Association), Dr. Manes S. Hecht (Detroit, Wayne County Rheumatic Fever Control Committee), Philip Butkovich (Victim of Rheumatic Fever).)
    - Motion Pictures, 1954 March 07; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 9)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-243-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest; Armand Denis documentary filmmaker photographer and Producer.)
    - Handling of Young Men, 1954 March 14; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 9)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-244-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest Clarence "Biggie" Munn (Athletic Director of Michigan State College).)
    - France, 1954 March 21; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 9)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-245-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program discussing of culture and religion in rural France. Featuring guests: Father Pierre Poirier (National Chaplain of the Rural Family Movement, Paris), Dr. Donat Gauthier (former Counselor Agent for France).)
    - Trip Around the World, 1954 March 28; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-246-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest Miss Betty Nelson (Teacher Fordson High School, Dearborn).)
    - Situation in Indochina, 1954 April 11; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-247-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: General S.L.A. Marshall (Detroit News Military Critic).)
    - Easter Sunday, 1954 April 18; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-248-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest Right Reverend Richard S. Emrich (Bishop of the Episcopal Diocese of Detroit).)
    - Michigan Hospital Week, 1954 May 02; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-249-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Danny Thomas, Mrs. Edward D. Spalding (Detroit Area Council of Hospital Auxiliaries).)
    - Trip to Europe, 1954 April 09; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-250-1]; (A portion begining at 7:20 skips and repeats multiple times, possibly from an edit on original disc. In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest Joseph Hainline.)
    - Armed Forces Day, 1954 May 16; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-251-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest Lt. General Emmett O'Donnell (Deputy Chief of Staff, Personnel, United States Air Force).)
    - Presbyterian Church, 1954 May 23; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-252-1]; (Tape 1; In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Rev. Harold Voekel (Chaplain among captured prisoners in Korea), Dr. Charles Leber (General Secretary of Board of Foreign Missions of Presbyterian Church). Topics discussed include the Church's activities in Korea.)
    - Presbyterian Church, 1954 May 23; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-253-1]; (Tape 2; In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Rev. Harold Voekel (Chaplain among captured prisoners in Korea), Dr. Charles Leber (General Secretary of Board of Foreign Missions of Presbyterian Church). Topics discussed include the Church's activities in Korea.)
    - Decoration Day, 1954 May 30; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-254-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring marching band performances of patriotic songs. Guest on this program is Ellen Guest.)
    - United Negro College Fund, 1954 June 06; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-255-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: William T. Gossett (Vice President of Ford Motor Company and Chairman of the Steering Committee), Walker L. Cisler (President of the Detroit Edison Company and Chairman of the Drive), Dr. Alonzo G. Moron (President of Hampton Institute Hampton, Virginia).)
    - United States Overseas Information Program, 1954 June 27; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-256-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Mr. Stephan P. Munsing (Cultural Affairs Officer for U.S. Information Agency in Berlin), Professor Will Grohman (Professor of Fine Arts at Technical University of Berlin and Art Critic American Government Radio Station RIAS in Berlin).)
    - Independence Day, 1954 July 04; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-257-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Mr. Howard Peckham (Director, William L. Clements Library, Ann Arbor, Michigan), William Sheehan (WJR Newscaster).)
    - Trip Around the World, 1954 July 11; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-258-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program discussing experiences in South and Southeast Asia. Guest is Mrs. Louis Carpenter (Assistant Foreign Student Advisor, Michigan State College).)
    - Grand Trunk Railroad, 1954 July 18; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-259-1]; (Tape 1; In Our Opinion radio program discussing the Grand Trunk Railroad and the last Port Huron - Detroit passenger train; (Guests: Mr. Hayward Abelwhite (Greenfield Village), Mr. David Nadeau (Greenfield Village), Frank Edison Smith (Grand Trunk Engineer), John F. Kramer (Station Master at Grand Trunk), John Burrows (Relief Station Master, Grand Trunk), Charles Hawkins (Grand Trunk Conductor), William K. Gibb (Grand Trunk Conductor), Louis A. Harnack (Mount Clemens Station Agent, retired).)
    - Grand Trunk Railroad, 1954 July 18; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-260-1]; (Tape 2; In Our Opinion radio program discussing the Grand Trunk Railroad and the last Port Huron - Detroit passenger train; (Guests: Mr. Hayward Abelwhite (Greenfield Village), Mr. David Nadeau (Greenfield Village), Frank Edison Smith (Grand Trunk Engineer), John F. Kramer (Station Master at Grand Trunk), John Burrows (Relief Station Master, Grand Trunk), Charles Hawkins (Grand Trunk Conductor), William K. Gibb (Grand Trunk Conductor), Louis A. Harnack (Mount Clemens Station Agent, retired).)
    - Indochina, 1954 July 25; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-261-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program discussing the end of the First Indochina War (following the Geneva Conference). Guest is Mr. Jean Beliard, member of the French Counsel.)
    - [Indochina], 1954 July 25; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-292-1]; (Uncertain about topic. Possibly Part 2 of Indochina tape)
    - "Indochina", August 1, 1954 (Box 10)
      (Guests: General S.A.L. Marshall (Military Critic of the Detroit News)
      (The surface of the disc was very noisy)
    - Africa, 1954 August 08; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-263-1]; (Part 1; In Our Opinion radio program discussing missionary work in Africa, guests: Right Reverend Stephen Tomusange (Assistant Bishop of the Upper Nile), Reverend Stanley Moore (Headmaster of the High School at Gulu), Mrs. Stanley Moore (lay representative of Anglican Congress).)
    - Africa, 1954 August 09; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-264-1]; (Part 2; In Our Opinion radio program discussing missionary work in Africa, guests: Right Reverend Stephen Tomusange (Assistant Bishop of the Upper Nile), Reverend Stanley Moore (Headmaster of the High School at Gulu), Mrs. Stanley Moore (lay representative of Anglican Congress).)
    - Mediterranean Cruise, 1954 August 15; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-265-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program discussing his touring of Southern Europe and the Mediterranean guest Robert L. Jillson (Redford High School Graduate, Winner of Harold Harding Essay Contest).)
    - South American Immunity to Disease, 1954 August 22; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-266-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest Dr. Eugene H. Payne (Medical Research Staff Parke Davis and Company).)
    - Internships for Foreign Journalists, 1954 August 29; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-267-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Mr. Robi Chakravorti (Calcutta, India).)
    - Trip to Europe, 1954 September 05; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-268-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program discussing the prospects of a "United States of Europe", politics in London, and other topics and experiences about Europe. Guest is Mr. C. J. Huddleston (Executive Vice President, Wabeek State Bank).)
    - Michigan State College, 1954 September 12; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-269-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Dr. John A. Hannah (President, Michigan State College).)
    - St. Andrew's Youth Movement, 1954 September 19; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-270-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Dr. Paul Rusch (Executive Director, Kiyosato Educational Experiment).)
    - St. Lawrence Seaway, 1954 September 26; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-271-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Mr. Troy H. Browning (President, T. H. Browning Steanship Lines).)
    - Old Mariner's Church, 1954 October 03; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-272-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Reverend Irwin C. Johnson (Rector of St. John's Episcopal Church and acting Rector of Mariner's Church), Mr. George W. Stark (President, Detroit Historical Commission, Senior Warden of Mariner's Church).)
    - World Tour, 1954 October 10; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-273-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Mr. William H. Ramsay (Director, Eastern Hemisphere Operations, Parke Davis & Company).)
    - Surrender of Lt. Gen. Burgoyne, 1954 October 17; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-274-1]; (Tape 1; In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Mr. Howard H. Peckham (Director, Clements Library, U of M, Ann Arbor), Jim Vinall (WJR Newscaster).)
    - Surrender of Lt. General Burgoyne, 1954 October 17; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-275-1]; (Tape 2; In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Mr. Howard H. Peckham (Director, Clements Library, U of M, Ann Arbor), Jim Vinall (WJR Newscaster).)
    - Vietnam, 1954 November 17; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 10)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-276-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Dr. Edward W. Weidner (Professor and Head of Political Science Dept. and Public Administration, MSC), Dr. Wesley R. Fishel (Associate Professor of Political Science, MSC), James H. Denison (Administrative Assistant to President John A. Hannah, Michigan State College).)
    - Detroit Police Department, 1954 November 14; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-277-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Superintendent Edwin S. Morgan, Commissioner Edward S. Piggins.)
    - Good Turn Day-Goodwill Industries and Boy Scouts, 1954 November 21; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-278-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Mr. Amos R. Shields (Scout Executive of the Detroit Area Council of Boy Scouts of America), Mr. Harold H. McKinnon (Executive Secretary of the Goodwill Industries of Detroit), Miss Evelyn Herrala, Mr. John Bell (Scout Master in Detroit))
    - Salvation Army, 1954 November 28; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-279-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Lt. Colonel T. M. Larsen (Divisional Commander), Major Oscar Agre, Envoy Arthur Truesdale, John Cunard (Harbor Lights Corps).)
    - Schools, 1954 December 05; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-280-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Roy E. Larsen (Publisher of Time, Incorporated and Chairman of the National Citizens Commission for the Public Schools).)
    - Israel's Judicial System, 1954 December 12; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-281-1]; (Tape 1; In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Justice S. Zalman Cheshin (Deputy President of the Supreme Court of the State of Israel).)
    - Israel's Judicial System, 1954 December 12; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-282-1]; (Tape 2; In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Justice S. Zalman Cheshin (Deputy President of the Supreme Court of the State of Israel).)
    - Israel's Judicial System, 1954 December 12; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-283-1]; (Tape 3; In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Justice S. Zalman Cheshin (Deputy President of the Supreme Court of the State of Israel).)
  - 1955
    - Peaceful Atomic Development, 1955 January 19; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-284-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Walker L. Cisler (President, Detroit Edison Company and Chairman of Funds for Peaceful Atomic Development).)
    - United Nations, 1955 January 16; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-285-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Mr. Charles H. Mahoney (President of Great Lakes Mutual Life Insurance Co. and first regular delegate to United Nations from Michigan))
    - Department of the Interior, 1955 February 13; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-286-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guest: Douglas McKay (Secretary of the Department of the Interior))
    - St. Lawrence Seaway, 1955 May 01; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-287-1]; (On the topic of shipping, history, and economic use of the St. Lawrence Seaway featuring guests: Dr. N. R. Danielian (President of Great Lakes-St. Lawrence Association))
    - Juvenile Delinquency, 1955 June 05; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-288-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program on the topic of juvenile crime featuring guests: Judge George Edwards.)
    - The Philippine Islands, 1955 June 19; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-289-1]; (In Our Opinion radio program featuring guests: Senator Homer Ferguson (U.S. Ambassador to the Philippines).)
    - Resume of Old Programs, 1955 June 26; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 11)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-290-1]; (Bud Guest appearing on older George Cushing programs.)
    - No title, November 14, 1955 (Box 11)
  - Undated
    - No title, Undated (Box 11)